americaneagle.com 2019-08-01

# Privacy Statement | Americaneagle.com

**Effective Date 5.17.18  
**This privacy statement describes how Americaneagle.com collects and uses the personal information you provide on our Web site: [www.americaneagle.com](https://www.americaneagle.com/). It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personal information and how you can access and update this information. If you have questions or complaints regarding our privacy policy or practices, please contact us at [info@americaneagle.com](mailto:info@americaneagle.com).

Americaneagle.com complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States.  Americaneagle.com has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles.  If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Americaneagle.com commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding our Privacy Shield policy should first contact:

Americaneagle.com   
Attn: Privacy Officer   
2600 S. River Road Des Plaines, IL 60018  

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

**Information We Collect**  
Americaneagle.com is committed to preserving your right to privacy. While we don't ask for any registration or personal information to browse our site, some information about your server address, Web browser, and computer system are automatically transmitted to our Web servers so that we can operate our site on the Internet. Americaneagle.com does not collect identifying information about You (such as Your name, address, telephone number, and email address) unless You voluntarily submit that information to us through our Contact Us page, our Americaneagle.com Newsletter page, to request a quote or other means. If you choose to apply for a job with Americaneagle.com we will collect information such as your name, email address, phone number and resume. We will only use this information for the purposes of reviewing your application for a position. We will only retain the information you submit for one year. Americaneagle.com stores its customer information in a password-protected database to fulfill your requests for certain services. All information You submit to us is confidential and we do not sell or otherwise disclose such information to third parties.

**Service Providers  
**We use other third parties to allow you to post comments on our blog by logging in using your social media or OpenID login information, and a customer support company to provide Live Chat to assist you if you have questions while using our site or regarding our services. When you sign up for our services, we will share your personal information only as necessary for the third party to provide that service.  

Solely for purposes of providing our services, we may share Your sanitized collected data with our contracted IT service providers.  These companies provide services such as IT and system administration and hosting, credit card processing, research and analytics, marketing, customer support and data enrichment.  Our service providers are located in this country.

Communication From The Site  
Newsletters  
If you wish to subscribe to our newsletter(s), we will use your name and email address to send the newsletter to you. If you wish to no longer receive these newsletters you may follow the unsubscribe instructions contained in each of the email communications you receive.

Service-related Announcements  
We will send you strictly service-related announcements on rare occasions when it is necessary to do so. For instance, if our service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, we might send you an email.

Generally, you may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. If you do not wish to receive them, you have the option to deactivate your account.

Tell-A-Friend  
If you choose to use our referral service to email a page from our site to a friend, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Americaneagle.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program.

Your friend may contact us at [info@americaneagle.com](mailto:info@americaneagle.com) to request that we remove this information from our database.

**Right To Access to Personally Identifiable Information  
**If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, delete/deactivate it by emailing our Customer Support at customerservice@americaneagle.com. We will respond to your request to access within 30 days.

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at info@americaneagle.com. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

Legal Disclaimer  
Americaneagle.com is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). There is a possibility, under certain conditions, for you to invoke binding arbitration. For more information, please visit the following link: <https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction>

We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request to any other third party with your prior consent to do so if Americaneagle.com is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, you will be notified via email and/or a prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

In the context of an onward transfer, a Privacy Shield organization has responsibility for the processing of personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Americaneagle.com shall remain liable under the Principles if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles, unless the organization proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. Beyond the limited use of a comments manager and chat service, Americaneagle.com does not transfer personal information to third parties. Therefore, the provision regarding liability for the actions of agent processors does not broadly apply.

**Security  
**The security of your personal information is important to us. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. Our websites, [www.americaneagle.com](https://www.americaneagle.com/) and jobs.americaneagle.com are fully encrypted over the https secure protocol. If you have any questions about security on our Web site, you can contact us at info@americaneagle.com.

**Tracking Technologies  
**Cookies  
A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies on this site. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personally identifiable information you submit while on our site.

We use session ID cookies not persistent cookies. We use session cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site. A session ID cookie expires when you close your browser. A persistent cookie remains on your hard drive for an extended period of time. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions provided in your Internet browser's "help" file.

If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some areas of our site, such as contests or surveys, will be limited.

The use of cookies by our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers is not covered by our privacy statement. We do not have access or control over these cookies. Our partners, affiliates, tracking utility company, service providers use session ID cookies to make it easier for you to navigate our site.

Clear Gifs  
We and our or our third party advertising partner employ a software technology called clear gifs (a.k.a. Web Beacons/Web Bugs), that help us better manage content on our site by informing us what content is effective. Clear gifs are tiny graphics with a unique identifier, similar in function to cookies, and are used to track the online movements of Web users. In contrast to cookies, which are stored on a user's computer hard drive, clear gifs are embedded invisibly on Web pages and are about the size of the period at the end of this sentence. We do not tie the information gathered by clear gifs to our customers' personally identifiable information.

We use clear gifs in our HTML-based emails to let us know which emails have been opened by recipients. This allows us to gauge the effectiveness of certain communications and the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns. If you would like to opt-out of these emails, please see "Communications From The Site."

Log Files  
As is true of most Web sites, we use third-party tracking services to gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data.

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

Google Analytics  
This Web site uses a tool called "Google Analytics" to collect information about use of the site. Google Analytics collects information such as how often users visit this site, what pages they visit when they do so, and what other sites they used prior to coming to this site. We use the information we get from Google Analytics only to improve this site. Google Analytics collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this site, rather than your name or other identifying information. We do not combine the information collected through the use of Google Analytics with personally identifiable information. Although Google Analytics plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this site, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google. Google's ability to use and share information collected by Google Analytics about your visits to this site is restricted by the Google Analytics Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy. You can prevent Google Analytics from recognizing you on return visits to this site by disabling cookies on your browser.

**Links To Other Sites  
**This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by Americaneagle.com. Please be aware that we, Americaneagle.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy statements of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

**Social Media Widgets  
**Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button [and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site]. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**Testimonials  
**With your consent we may post your testimonial along with your name. If you want your testimonial removed please contact us at info@americaneagle.com.

**Public Forum  
**Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at marketing@americaneagle.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**Notifications Of Privacy Statement Changes  
**We may update this privacy statement to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.
